A data center might have multiple layers of defense.
We would have administrative controls such as policies and procedures,
then logical or technical controls which include programming to limit access.
There are also physical controls which we sometimes
forget about in our highly technical world.
Regardless of how much we focus on cloud computing and virtualization.
There is always a physical location where information is being stored
or processed in a physical hard drive in a physical computer.
Even in a data center in a
large organization that provides cloud computing services.
For example,
there is still a physical aspect of information storage and processing.